<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Breakfastisready</title>
        <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/tags/goals/</link>
        <description>Latest blog posts from Breakfastisready</description>

        
        <language>en-us</language>
        

        

        

        

        
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        

        
        <atom:link href="https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/tags/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        

        
            
        <item>
          <title>Here cometh 2021</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/here-cometh-2021/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/here-cometh-2021/</guid>
          <description>This is in continuation to a previous post, which you can read here. In that post, I try to lay out all the facets of my personality that I am unhappy with and I would like to vanish along with the year 2020. This post will be more hopeful and will lay out how I could change what I was and what lies on the path ahead. These will be the answer to the grievances, my jawab-e-shikwa.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Death to my 2020-self</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/death-to-my-2020-self/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/death-to-my-2020-self/</guid>
          <description>Yesterday, I was watching the Netflix show Death to 2020. It’s a funny mockumentry with a stellar starcast about a horrible year that will be over soon. Watch the trailer here. It is up to anyone’s guess what 2021 will be like, but by all means it is very difficult for the coming year to be worse than what it was.
Personally, it was a horrible year for myself too. With the pandemic spreading, I joined Twitter to keep up with all the developments and quickly developed opinions about Indian politics and climate change, some of which I will consider quite radical now.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Crash landed on a K-drama</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/crash-landed-on-a-k-drama/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/crash-landed-on-a-k-drama/</guid>
          <description>I recently started watching a Korean drama called Crash landing on you. In this blog post, I will mostly talk about my thoughts about watching this romantic fantasy series, without giving away too much (so no spoilers). So far I have only seen the first six episodes. I will write a more complete review after I finish.
Here’s a trailer of the series:   I was hesitant at first. I thought that this show is just below me.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Dejected, is this how the days would pass?</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/dejected-is-this-how-the-days-would-pass/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/dejected-is-this-how-the-days-would-pass/</guid>
          <description>Here is a ghazal by the Urdu poet Jaun Eliya. You can read it in Hindi, Urdu and English in the original words here, with word meanings on highlight. Additionally, if you want to follow the pauses and the breaks that the poet himself makes while reciting it, you can check out this video of a mushaira in Dubai.
I have been thinking about these lines for a while now. Below, I have done a translation of the ghazal in English, couplet-wise.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Initializing my new blog</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/initializing-my-new-blog/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/initializing-my-new-blog/</guid>
          <description>New beginnings Here is a couplet Dr. Bashir Badr.
कोई फूल धूप की पत्तियों में हरे रिबन से बँधा हुआ
वो ग़ज़ल का लहजा नया नया न कहा हुआ न सुना हुआ
Here’s a translation in English:
A flower, leaves seemingly like the sun, tied together with a green ribbon,
The poetry here is very new, never before seen, never before heard of.</description>
        </item>
            
        
    </channel>
</rss>
