<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Breakfastisready</title>
        <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/tags/shayari/</link>
        <description>Latest blog posts from Breakfastisready</description>

        
        <language>en-us</language>
        

        

        

        

        
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        

        
        <atom:link href="https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/tags/shayari/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        

        
            
        <item>
          <title>Exchanges with a friend</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2022/04/exchanges-with-a-friend/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2022/04/exchanges-with-a-friend/</guid>
          <description>Recently, I had some discussions with a friend of mine. Let’s call this person X.
In a tweet that I had recently posted, I expressed interest in knowing better the history of Tipu Sultan. I am interested in Indian history in general, that the politically controversial nature of Tipu’s legacy makes it worth knowing more about this topic.
X had some strong opinions about this topic and X quickly started confronting me about it.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Learning to swim</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/12/learning-to-swim/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/12/learning-to-swim/</guid>
          <description>Hello! How are you, my dear blog?
Today I went to the local swimming pool to learn to swim. I am not very good ad this activity. In this post, I’m just going to blurt out some thoughts about what I think about all this.
This is going to be a bunch of advice for people who want to get into it, or mostly just a set of instructions that I want to remember myself</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Court: Review</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/05/court-review/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/05/court-review/</guid>
          <description>This is a film review of the film Court. This film has been around since 2014 but I just saw it.
Follow the spoiler warnings and you can read this review without getting the film spoiled.
What is it about? It is a courtroom drama created by some guy called Chaitanya Tamhane. The film tries very hard to show a realistic courtroom
The film is also very much about race relations in the United States.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Get out: Review</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/05/get-out-review/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/05/get-out-review/</guid>
          <description>I saw Get Out, a 2017 film by Jordan Peele. This film was recommended to me by TG.
Follow the spoiler warnings and you can read this review without getting the film spoiled.
What is it about? The film is written and directed by Jordan Peele, who is definitely on a prolonged high-point in his career since the last few years. His last few films have gotten numerous accolades and love from critics.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Nagarkirtan: Review</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/05/nagarkirtan-review/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/05/nagarkirtan-review/</guid>
          <description>I recently came across a 2017 Bengali film called Nagarkirtan. This film was recommended to me by AP. The film is available on the streaming platform Hoichoi TV.
The film is a beautiful work of art. I will clearly mark the point after which this post contains spoilers.
What is it about? The film is written and directed by Kaushik Ganguly, who is famous for making movies about oppressed classes and sexualities.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Modern Times: Review</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/04/modern-times-review/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/04/modern-times-review/</guid>
          <description>I have been very busy in the past few months. Lately, I have had a little bit more of time in my hands to watch films and think about them. I have explored some Charlie Chaplin films. Some of the films were suggested to me by RS. Here are the films that I saw.
Film name Year of release The Kid 1921 City Lights 1931 Modern Times 1936 The Great Dictator 1940 Each of these films is excellent and each one of them merits a blog post in itself.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Sketch of a person</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/03/sketch-of-a-person/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/03/sketch-of-a-person/</guid>
          <description>This is a caricature drawn on my Remarkable 2 during a video call with my friend AM.
GitHubTwitterMastodonEmailRSS</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Permutation City: Review</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/02/permutation-city-review/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/02/permutation-city-review/</guid>
          <description>This is a spoiler-free book review of Permutation City. This book was written in 1994 by the Australian mathematician and writer Greg Egan. He has a very peculiar background, which is that of mathematics and programming. In mathematics, he is known for having solved a combinatorics problem. The problem is very easy to explain, there’s even this Quanta magazine article about it.
What is it about? It is a fiction based on the theme of uploading one’s consciousness to a computer.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Rude boy</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/02/rude-boy/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/02/rude-boy/</guid>
          <description>I recently bought a Remarkable 2.
This is a political cartoon I made on it. It’s about the India’s right wing reacting to Rihanna.
Let me know what you think!
GitHubTwitterMastodonEmailRSS</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Albert Pinto ko gussa kyun aata hai: Review</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/01/albert-pinto-ko-gussa-kyun-aata-hai-review/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/01/albert-pinto-ko-gussa-kyun-aata-hai-review/</guid>
          <description>Lately, I had seen a film called Salim Langde pe mat ro. I wrote a review of that film in a previous blog post. I had really liked that film, so I tried to watch another film by the same director Saeed Mirza called Albert Pinto ko gussa kyon aata hai. The title in English would translate as “Why does Albert Pinto get angry?”.
In this post, I will give a spoiler free review of the film and my thoughts about it.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Why cry at how long the path of love is?</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/01/why-cry-at-how-long-the-path-of-love-is/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/01/why-cry-at-how-long-the-path-of-love-is/</guid>
          <description>The following is my discussion about a ghazal written by the Urdu poet Mir Taqi Mir. But who is he?
Mir Taqi Mir (1723-1810) was a contemporary of Mirza Ghalib operating in the city of Lucknow. He was one of the first Urdu poets and he has pretty much shaped the language itself. Of course comparisons will be made between Mir and Ghalib and Wikipedia even has this section about what Ghalib said about Mir.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Salim langde pe mat ro: Review</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/01/salim-langde-pe-mat-ro-review/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2021/01/salim-langde-pe-mat-ro-review/</guid>
          <description>I just saw a fantastic film called Salim Langde pe mat ro. This film was suggested to me by RS. In this post, I will give a spoiler free review of the film and my thoughts about it.
The entire film is on Youtube. You can watch it below.
What is it about? It’s definitely not some famous film and the name sounds bizarre. An English translation of the name would be “Don’t cry for Salim the Lame”.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Here cometh 2021</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/here-cometh-2021/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/here-cometh-2021/</guid>
          <description>This is in continuation to a previous post, which you can read here. In that post, I try to lay out all the facets of my personality that I am unhappy with and I would like to vanish along with the year 2020. This post will be more hopeful and will lay out how I could change what I was and what lies on the path ahead. These will be the answer to the grievances, my jawab-e-shikwa.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Here cometh 2021</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/here-cometh-2021/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/here-cometh-2021/</guid>
          <description>This is in continuation to a previous post, which you can read here. In that post, I try to lay out all the facets of my personality that I am unhappy with and I would like to vanish along with the year 2020. This post will be more hopeful and will lay out how I could change what I was and what lies on the path ahead. These will be the answer to the grievances, my jawab-e-shikwa.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Death to my 2020-self</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/death-to-my-2020-self/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/death-to-my-2020-self/</guid>
          <description>Yesterday, I was watching the Netflix show Death to 2020. It’s a funny mockumentry with a stellar starcast about a horrible year that will be over soon. Watch the trailer here. It is up to anyone’s guess what 2021 will be like, but by all means it is very difficult for the coming year to be worse than what it was.
Personally, it was a horrible year for myself too. With the pandemic spreading, I joined Twitter to keep up with all the developments and quickly developed opinions about Indian politics and climate change, some of which I will consider quite radical now.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Crash landed on a K-drama</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/crash-landed-on-a-k-drama/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/crash-landed-on-a-k-drama/</guid>
          <description>I recently started watching a Korean drama called Crash landing on you. In this blog post, I will mostly talk about my thoughts about watching this romantic fantasy series, without giving away too much (so no spoilers). So far I have only seen the first six episodes. I will write a more complete review after I finish.
Here’s a trailer of the series: I was hesitant at first. I thought that this show is just below me.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Dejected, is this how the days would pass?</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/dejected-is-this-how-the-days-would-pass/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/dejected-is-this-how-the-days-would-pass/</guid>
          <description>Here is a ghazal by the Urdu poet Jaun Eliya. You can read it in Hindi, Urdu and English in the original words here, with word meanings on highlight. Additionally, if you want to follow the pauses and the breaks that the poet himself makes while reciting it, you can check out this video of a mushaira in Dubai.
I have been thinking about these lines for a while now. Below, I have done a translation of the ghazal in English, couplet-wise.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title>Initializing my new blog</title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/initializing-my-new-blog/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/2020/12/initializing-my-new-blog/</guid>
          <description>New beginnings Here is a couplet Dr. Bashir Badr.
कोई फूल धूप की पत्तियों में हरे रिबन से बँधा हुआ
वो ग़ज़ल का लहजा नया नया न कहा हुआ न सुना हुआ
Here’s a translation in English:
A flower, leaves seemingly like the sun, tied together with a green ribbon,
The poetry here is very new, never before seen, never before heard of.
You can continue reading the rest of the poem here.</description>
        </item>
            
        <item>
          <title></title>
          <link>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/1/01/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://www.breakfastisready.xyz/blog/1/01/</guid>
          <description>jjj++ author = “Breakfastisready” title= “Posting after a while” draft = false date = “2022-12-22” description = “Still alive” tags= [“personal”] categories= [“miscellaneous”] +++
Just writing a post to check if my new setup works.
I recently bought a Pinephone Pro with a keyboard attachment.
The setup works very well and is very handy. Typing experience is okay. The best part is being able to use vim on the go.</description>
        </item>
            
        
    </channel>
</rss>
